Anne Nguyen . Jarvis Consulting

Prior to pursuing a career in data science, I completed my first undergraduate degree at Waterloo in Health Science, where I picked up my interest in technology through participating in the VeloCity residency startup initiative. From this interest, I pursued a B.Sc. in computer science at Ryerson University, which I completed recently. In my spare time, I write and publish creative writing online, go to board game cafés with my friends, and watch and listen to a significant amount of baseball. During a machine learning course, I took the opportunity to analyze a decade's worth of baseball statistics to analyze individual player performance - information I knew as a fan reading FanGraph analysis, but never computed or compiled myself. Through this course, I became more earnestly interested in data science.

Skills

Proficient: Java, Bash, SQL, Agile/Scrum

Competent: C/C++, NumPy, pandas, Python, Spring, Spring Boot.

Familiar: HTML/CSS, PHP, Javascript.

Development Projects

Project source code.

- Cluster Monitor Agent: An internal tool that monitors the server cluster resources. It records the hardware specifications of each node (server) and monitors resource usage such as CPU and memory utilization in real-time. The collected data is stored in a locally hosted PostgreSQL database on a designated primary server node. This tool allows for report generation, which can inform future resource planning such as adding or removing servers based on their usage and activity.
- Core Java Apps: Three Java applications. (1) Java implementation of the grep Bash command-line utility used for searching through plain-text data sets for lines that match a text pattern. (2) Java application that allows users to connect to a PostgreSQL database and create, update, read, and delete data from its tables. (3) Command-line application that allows its user to post, show, and delete Twitter posts using the Twitter REST API.
- SpringBoot App: In-process. A trading application that buys and sells the stock. It retrieves up-to-date IEX Quote data, submits buy and sell orders on the behalf of a trader profile, and records completed and pending transactions.

• Cloud & DevOps: Not started.

• Hadoop: Not started.

• Spark/Scala: Not started.

Professional Experiences

Software Developer, Jarvis, Toronto (2019-Present): Completing a comprehensive development program on core BigData technologies used by industry experts and working on projects that include Cloud, DevOps, Java, Hadoop/Spark. Responsible for performing scrum master duties in Agile-based team projects to ensure team cohesion and collaboration.

Administrative/Clerical Assistant, Toronto (2015-2018): Scanned and organized weekly invoices and over 5,000 donor documents for the transition from paper to electronic records. Entered, maintained, and updated database with current donor contact information. Provided timely clerical support to administration and marketing departments.

UI Designer, Toronto (2015): Collaborated with a software developer to create a Bluetooth application. Designed user interface components such as recreating the company logo and menu navigation tabs with Adobe Photoshop CS3.

Education & Academic Projects

Ryerson University (2015-2019), Bachelors of Science, Computer Science - Drone Simulator (C/C++): Developed a user-controlled drone that can navigate a cityscape capable of shooting missiles, implemented drone and environment (buildings, roads) objects using modular design, implemented drone movement, rotation, collision detection, and toggleable cameras, used OpenGL/GLUT libraries, Phong lighting model, and texture mapping.

- Machine Learning Project (Python): Utilized NumPy, Pandas, and Scikit-Learn to apply different machine learning concepts, cleaned and prepared datasets used to train Naïve-Bayes, logistic regression, and support vector machine learning models. Used 2000-2017 statistics representing 1,200 professional baseball players to train logistical regression and Naïve-Bayes learning models to predict 2018 performance.
- Head's Up Badugi A.I. Player (Java): Created a competitive AI agent that played heads-up pot-limit badugi capable of deciding cards to discard to improve the winning likelihood and altering its bet aggression based on hand content, bluff preferences determined by win momentum. Placed 4th and tied for 6th place in two tournament runs with 20 and 21 AI participants.

University of Waterloo (2009-2014), Bachelor of Science, Health Studies.

- NeuroFit Progam Evaluation Project: Compiled information about program delivery and data collection methodology through a coordinator interview, reviewing existing program materials, and 4 on-site observations, conducted community scan and literature review to determine program need and efficacy in meeting program goals, and prepared written report outlining a detailed evaluation study plan for program stakeholders.
- Pharmacare & Catastrophic Drug Coverage Policy Brief: Conducted literature review, researched existing catastrophic drug coverage plan, summarized policy options to address rising financial burden due to increasing pharmaceutical cost and prepared written recommendations and proposed timeline for policy implementation.

Certificates & Awards & Activities

• Ryerson University: Dean's List (2016-17, 2018-19).